{
  "exam_name": "C Programming Set 4",
  "total_marks": 20,
  "time_limit": 20,
  "questions": [
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5;<br> printf(\"%d\", x++ * ++x);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "25",
              "B": "35",
              "C": "30",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "B"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 3;<br> printf(\"%d\", x++ + ++x);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "8",
              "B": "9",
              "C": "7",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 0;<br> for (; x < 10; x++) {<br> \tif (x % 2 == 0)<br> \t\tcontinue;<br>\tprintf(\"%d \", x);<br>}<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "0 2 4 6 8",
              "B": "1 3 5 7 9",
              "C": "1 3 5 7",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "B"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the return-type of the function sqrt()?",
          "options": {
              "a": "int",
              "b": "float",
              "c": "double",
              "d": "depends on the data type of the parameter"
          },
          "correct_answer": "c"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5;<br> int y = 2;<br> printf(\"%f\", (float)x / y);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "2.5",
              "B": "2",
              "C": "2.0",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5;<br> int *ptr = &x;<br> printf(\"%d\", (*ptr)++);<br> printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "5 6",
              "B": "5 5",
              "C": "6 6",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5;<br> int *ptr = &x;<br> printf(\"%d\", (*ptr) + 2);<br> printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "7 5",
              "B": "5 5",
              "C": "7 7",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
          "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int m() {<br> printf(\"hello\");<br>}<br> void main() {<br> int k = m();<br> printf(\"%d\", k);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "a": "hello5",
              "b": "Error",
              "c": "Nothing",
              "d": "Junk value"
          },
          "correct_answer": "d"
      },
      {
          "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int *m() {<br> int *p = 5;<br> return p;<br>}<br> void main() {<br> int *k = m();<br> printf(\"%d\", k);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "a": "5",
              "b": "Junk value",
              "c": "0",
              "d": "Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "d"
      },
      {
          "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>void m(int k) {<br> printf(\"hi\");<br>}<br> void m(double k) {<br> printf(\"hello\");<br>}<br> void main() {<br> m(3);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "a": "hi",
              "b": "hello",
              "c": "Compile time error",
              "d": "Nothing"
          },
          "correct_answer": "c"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int arr[] = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5};<br> printf(\"%d\", arr[5]);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "0",
              "B": "1",
              "C": "4",
              "D": "Undefined behavior"
          },
          "correct_answer": "D"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int arr[5] = {1, 2, 3};<br> printf(\"%d\", arr[4]);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "0",
              "B": "1",
              "C": "4",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "A"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5;<br> int *ptr = &x;<br> printf(\"%p\", ptr + 1);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "Address of x in hexadecimal format",
              "B": "5",
              "C": "Address of x in hexadecimal format + 1",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> char str[] = \"Hello, World!\";<br> printf(\"%s\", str + 7);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "Hello,",
              "B": "World!",
              "C": "o, World!",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "B"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the default return type if it is not specified in function definition?",
          "options": {
              "a": "void",
              "b": "int",
              "c": "double",
              "d": "short int"
          },
          "correct_answer": "b"
      },
      {
          "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>enum m {JAN, FEB, MAR};<br> enum m foo();<br> int main() {<br> enum m i = foo();<br> printf(\"%d\\n\", i);<br>}<br> int foo() {<br> return JAN;<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "a": "Compile time error",
              "b": "0",
              "c": "Depends on the compiler",
              "d": "Depends on the standard"
          },
          "correct_answer": "a"
      },
      {
          "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int x = 5;<br> void main() {<br> int x = 3;<br> printf(\"%d\", x);<br> {<br> x = 4;<br> }<br> printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "a": "Run time error",
              "b": "3 3",
              "c": "3 5",
              "d": "3 4"
          },
          "correct_answer": "d"
      },
      {
          "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>int main() {<br> printf(\"%d\", d++);<br>}<br> int d = 10;</pre>",
          "options": {
              "a": "9",
              "b": "10",
              "c": "11",
              "d": "Compile time error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "d"
      },
      {
          "question": "What will be the output of the following C code?<br><br><pre>static int x = 5;<br> void main() {<br> x = 9;<br> {<br> int x = 4;<br> }<br> printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "a": "9",
              "b": "4",
              "c": "5",
              "d": "0"
          },
          "correct_answer": "a"
      },
      {
          "question": "What is the output of the following program?<br><br><pre>void main() {<br> int x = 5;<br> int *ptr = &x;<br> printf(\"%d\", ++*ptr);<br> printf(\"%d\", x);<br>}</pre>",
          "options": {
              "A": "6 6",
              "B": "6 5",
              "C": "5 6",
              "D": "Compilation Error"
          },
          "correct_answer": "A"
      }
  ]
}
